[
  {
    "question": "Majority of flowering plants use a range of ______ as pollinating agents.",
    "answer": "animals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bees, butterflies, flies, beetles, wasps, ants, moths, birds (sunbirds and humming birds) and bats are the common ______ agents.",
    "answer": "pollinating"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the animals, insects, particularly ______ are the dominant biotic pollinating agents.",
    "answer": "bees"
  },
  {
    "question": "Even larger animals such as some primates (lemurs), arboreal rodents, or even reptiles like ______ have been reported as pollinators in some species.",
    "answer": "gecko lizard and garden lizard"
  },
  {
    "question": "Often flowers of animal-pollinated plants are specifically adapted for a particular ______ of animal.",
    "answer": "species"
  },
  {
    "question": "Majority of insect-pollinated flowers are large, colourful, fragrant and rich in ______.",
    "answer": "nectar"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the flowers are small, a number of flowers are clustered into an ______ to make them conspicuous.",
    "answer": "inflorescence"
  },
  {
    "question": "Animals are attracted to flowers by colour and/or ______.",
    "answer": "fragrance"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flowers pollinated by flies and beetles secrete ______ odours to attract these animals.",
    "answer": "foul"
  },
  {
    "question": "To sustain animal visits, the flowers have to provide ______ to the animals.",
    "answer": "rewards"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nectar and ______ grains are the usual floral rewards.",
    "answer": "pollen"
  },
  {
    "question": "For harvesting the rewards from the flower the animal visitor comes in contact with the ______ and the stigma.",
    "answer": "anthers"
  },
  {
    "question": "The body of the animal gets a coating of pollen grains, which are generally ______ in animal pollinated flowers.",
    "answer": "sticky"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the animal carrying pollen on its body comes in contact with the ______, it brings about pollination.",
    "answer": "stigma"
  },
  {
    "question": "In some species floral rewards are in providing safe places to lay ______.",
    "answer": "eggs"
  },
  {
    "question": "An example is that of the tallest flower of ______ which is about 6 feet in height.",
    "answer": "Amorphophallus"
  },
  {
    "question": "A similar relationship exists between a species of moth and the plant ______ where both species cannot complete their life cycles without each other.",
    "answer": "Yucca"
  }
]
